<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Curly Road]]></title><description><![CDATA[A starter blog demonstrating what Gatsby can do.]]></description><link>https://curlyroad.netlify.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 14:17:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[The Natural Hair Journey]]></title><description><![CDATA[Here in the Philippines, having hair texture other than straight is seen as unusual. A lot of girls I’ve known since I was younger have had…]]></description><link>https://curlyroad.netlify.com//the-natural-hair-journey/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://curlyroad.netlify.com//the-natural-hair-journey/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Here in the Philippines, having hair texture other than straight is seen as unusual. A lot of girls I’ve known since I was younger have had their hair straightened at least once, and some even regularly at once a year. Even I have had my hair straightened twice before.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to get started with the Curly Girl Method]]></title><description><![CDATA[Getting started with this method shouldn’t be too difficult. So what’s next after reading all about CGM?Prepare everything you need for the…]]></description><link>https://curlyroad.netlify.com//how-to/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://curlyroad.netlify.com//how-to/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Getting started with this method shouldn’t be too difficult. So what’s next after reading all about CGM?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Prepare everything you need for the final wash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For CGM to be successful, you’re going to have to do a final wash. The final wash is essential to clarify your hair and remove product build up from CG unapproved products, especially silicones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check for ingredients to avoid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are certain ingredients in shampoos and conditioners that are doing more harm than good to our hair.
These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sulfates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Silicones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parabens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for products without these ingredients can be tricky, but just type in the ingredients on this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.curlsbot.com/&quot;&gt;online tool&lt;/a&gt; and it will tell you if the product is CG approved or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your existing hair products have these ingredients, it’s better to stop using them now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prepare your product line-up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A shampoo with sulfate &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; or dishwashing liquid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conditioner of your choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gel or styling product of your choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microfiber towel or a cotton t-shirt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conditioner and gel or styling product &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; be CG approved. The shampoo with sulfate or dishwashing liquid is the key product to remove any build up on your hair and this will only be used once. Your usual bathing towel is no good for your hair now as well, as its texture will create too much friction against your hair and will disrupt the curl clumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Do the final wash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you’re all set, it’s time to do the final wash. This will only be done &lt;strong&gt;once&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use the shampoo or dishwashing liquid to wash your hair&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the most important step of the final wash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the shampoo, &lt;strong&gt;coat your hair with generous amount of conditioner&lt;/strong&gt;, making sure that every strand is coated. This is better done with your hair upside down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use your hands to squish the conditioner into your hair upwards to the roots&lt;/strong&gt;. This action will ensure that your hair will be thoroughly moisturized and your natural curl pattern will start to come out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rinse off about 3/4 the conditioner from your hair&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s better to leave some of the conditioner on your hair, this will reduce the amount gels or styling products needed after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dry your hair with the microfiber towel or cotton t-shirt&lt;/strong&gt; using the same squishing upward motion you did with the conditioner. The goal is to reduce friction as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply gel or any styling product&lt;/strong&gt; with the same squishing motion or with your palms touching together like you’re praying, and go along the length of your hair, by sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Air dry&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[TV Commercial]]></title><description><![CDATA[Coolot Styling GelVideoAudioScene 1: Girl 1 wakes up very early in the morningBackground musicScene 2: She spends a lot of time preparing…]]></description><link>https://curlyroad.netlify.com//tv-commercial/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://curlyroad.netlify.com//tv-commercial/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Coolot Styling Gel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Video&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Audio&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scene 1: Girl 1 wakes up very early in the morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Background music&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scene 2: She spends a lot of time preparing, especially on her curly hair&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Background music&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scene 3: She goes out and immediately a strong wind breezes past her&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sad background music&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scene 4: She touches her now frizzy hair and gets sad&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sad background music&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scene 5: Girl 2 with curly hair comes to her and recommends a product&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Nahanginan lang, frizzy kagad? Try Coolot Styling Gel!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scene 6: Girl 1 is preparing again and now using the styling gel on her hair&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“It has moisturizing ingredients that will keep your hair in place all day!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scene 7: Girl 1 and Girl 2 are seen walking together as wind breezes by them and their hair stays in place&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Thanks girl!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>